Guide to the Larry Neal papers
New York Public Library
- Reference Material
  - Subject File
    - Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee
      - 1967 (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
      - Statement by James Forman, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - International Seminar on Racial Discrimination and Colonialism in Southern Africa (Zambia), Agenda, Speeches, August, 1967 (Box 36, Folder 6-7)
      - Essay, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Surinam I Shall Molder Before I Shall be Taken, I Sought My Brother, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Van Der Zee, James, 1970-1976 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Van Peebles, Melvin, 1971-1972 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Malcolm X (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Zionism (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Articles, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 14-17)
  - Card File - Musicians, Richard Wright (Box 37)
    The Card File subseries, n.d. (.4 lin. ft.), consists of notes Neal prepared on jazz and blues musicians and on Richard Wright.
  - Annotated Books
    The Annotated Books subseries, ca. 1960-1978 (1 lin. ft.), consists of photocopies of annotated pages from books in Neal's library. The original books have been transferred to the General Research and Reference Division of the Schomburg Center. Authors include Kenneth Burke, Ralph Ellison, Addison Gayle, Jr., Ishmael Reed, and Askia Muhammad Toure. Topics of the books encompass literature (such as novels), language, music, politics, and history.
    - “A-Br” (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Burke, Kenneth (Box 38, Folder 2-3)
    - Cable, Mary (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - “C” (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - “D” (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - “E-Ga” (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - “Ga-Gw” (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - “Hal-Hask” (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - “Has-Her” (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - “Hi-Ja” (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - “J-Ki” (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - “Kr-M” (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - “O-Pe” (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - “Pl-Po” (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Reed, Ishmael (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - “R-Sh” (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Shapiro-Shakespeare (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - “Sh-To” (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - “Th-We” (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - “Wi” (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified Authors (Box 40, Folder 4)
- Writings By Other Authors
  The series is divided into two subseries: Essays, Short Stories, Poems, 1966-1979 (1 lin. ft.) focus on African-American and African topics by such authors as Amiri Baraka, John Blassingame, Hoyt Fuller, and Robert F. Thompson. The second subseries, Scripts, 1972-1977 (.8 lin. ft.), consists of playscripts and screenplays authored by a variety of writers including Hoyt Fuller, Earnest L. Hudson, Henry Edward Krehbiel, Ishmael Reed, Howard Sackler, and Douglas Turner Ward.
  - Essays, Short Stories, Poems
    - A. Philip Randolph Institute - A `Freedom Budget' For All Americans - Article, July 1966 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Alakoye, Adesanya - Poems, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Allen, Mayor Ivan - If You Were - Poem (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Allen, Samuel W. - Poetry and the National Conscience - Essay, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Anderson, S.E. - Let Nobody Turn Us 'Round - Short Story (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Baraka, Amiri - Not Just Survival: Revolution - Essay, Poems, 1964-1977 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Bassett, John - The Western Dream Turns Nightmare - Poem (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Bibbs, Hart LeRoi - Diet Book for Junkies - Short Story (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Black, W. Joseph - Harlem's Other Image - Essay, 1974 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Blassingame, J. (Editor) - The Poet's Vision of Black America - Compilation (Box 41, Folder 10-11)
    - Brierre, Jean F. - Louis Armstrong and Prayer to Olokun - Poems, 1970-1971 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Brown, Patricia L. (Shariat, Fahamisha) -
      - Black Ritual Theatre - Essay, Spring, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - A Woman's Voice: Black Woman Poets from Phyllis Wheatley to Angela Jackson - Essay, n.d.
    - Bullins, Ed - Black Theatre: The 70's - Evolutionary Changes - Essay, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Bush, Joseph - Phil Edwards: Perennial Olympian - Essay (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Cirino, Linda/Edmiston, Susan - Chapter - Harlem, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Cloud, Hamilton - Jazz and Capitalism: Never the Twain Shall Meet - Essay, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Cobb, Charles - “Proposal for an Afro-American Cultural and Educational Center”, Proposal, 1967 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Coleman, John - The Development of the Black Short Story - Dissertation Abstract, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Collings, Webb - One More Time - Short Story (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Committee of Concerned Blacks - Should American Blacks Tour South Africa to Entertain Africans - Essay (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Crouch, Stanley - Look Out Moan We Standing Round - Essay, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Cuelho, Art - Poems (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Cutter, Charles H. - Towards a Contextual Analysis of the African Mask: The Filmic Evidence of Dan Masks - Essay, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - Dent, Tom C. - The Ghetto of Desire (Inside Desire Version) - Essay (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Djenaba, Nneke, (nee Pat Ford) - Poems, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - Douglas, Max - Poems, pre 1970 (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - Dumas, Henry - `Ark of Bones' and Other Stories Strike and Fade” - Story, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - Economou, George - Poems (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - Essien-Udom, E.U. - Tribalism and Racism - Essay, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Farabi, Khadijah Nubian House Theatre - Poems, ca. 1976 (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - Farley, Jr., William H. - Summun Bukmun Umyun - Short Story, Poems, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - Franklin, Clarence - Poems (Box 41, Folder 33)
    - Fuller, Hoyt (Box 41, Folder 34)
      - Question: What is Black Power, Daddy? Answer: `?' - Essay, n.d.
      - Richard Kluger's Simple Justice - Teleplay, 1979
    - Gibson, Kenneth Morality and City Government - Speech (Box 41, Folder 35)
    - Goss, Clay - The Way Before - Essay, 1970 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Graves, A - Poems, 1968 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Harris, Michael DeHart - The Development of a Non-Materialistic Approach to Painting, - Essay, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Hawkins, Richard C. - Dicky's Dictionary of Dark Definitions! (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Hurston, Zora Neale - Poems, 1919 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Hemphill, A. Marcus - A Touch of Sweden - Novel (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Henderson, David - Keep On Pushing (Harlem Riots/Summer/1964) (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Hughes, Langston - The Backlash Blues - Poem (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Jennings, Regina Belvey - Poems, 1979, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - Open Windows to My Song....
      - City Life in America
      - Tankas and Cinquains
    - Jennings, Regina Belvey - Stories (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - Ebony Dreams, 1977
      - A Love for the People, 1979
    - Jones, Barbara (Odaro) - Alafia - Poem (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Key, Ted - Emma's First National Bank - Television Treatment (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Kilgore, James - Toward the Dark Tower - Incomplete - Essay, 1970 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - King, Eric S. - Portrait of the Manchild in Wynnefield - Essay (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - King, Josie M./Blake, J. Herman - Teaching Negro History: A Dual Emphasis - Essay (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Lane, Pinkie Gordon - Songs to the Dialysis Machine - Poem (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Llorens, David - Damn the American Dream - Story (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - Mayfield, Julian - Black Power and White Response - Speech, November 28, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Merriam, Alan P. - The African Idiom in Music - Conference Papers, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - Milner, Ron - Ray: A Pantomine - Short Story, 1966 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - Mweusi, A. - Steps to Liberation - Essay, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Neal, Evelyn - The Train Has Been Gone a Long Time, and You Missed It - Review Essay (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Ogilvie, D.T. - Sketches in Black - Poems (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - Otis, Jr., Clarence - Kwame Nkrumah and Some Tenets of Leadership - Essay, 1975 (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - Partisan Review - A Statement on the New Cultural Conservatism - Essay, 1972 (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - Phillips, Anne Rutledge - Poems, 1968 (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - Reed, Clarence - Not Forever Tears - Poems, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 27)
    - Roebuck, Daniel - Polemics and Purity: The New Masses and the Development of Literary Communism in America - Essay, 1975 (Box 42, Folder 28)
    - Russell, Bill - Poems (Box 42, Folder 29)
    - Simon, James A. - Autobiography (Box 42, Folder 30)
    - Smith, Warren P. - Never the Fool of Time - Story, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Spellman, A.B. - Poems Preliminary Proposal for Black Journal, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Stanford, Max - What Road for Black Power (The New Direction) - Essay (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Stewart, James - We - Poems (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Stewart, Jimmie - Black Musical Nationalism and Jazz - Incomplete - Essay (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Sultan, Gene - Larry Neal at the Gotham, Poem, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Thelwell, Mike - As a Sounding Brass and a Talking Cymbal: Modernist Fallacies and the Responsibility of the Black Writer - Essay (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Thompson, Robert F. - The Sign of the Divine King: Yoruba Bead-Embroidered Crowns with Veil and Bird Decorations - Article (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Wagner, Jane - J.T. - T.V. Outline (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Williams, Marshall - A Translation of a Fictitious Letter Found Backstage at a Theatre, 1978 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified Author - Comparative Race and the Ethnic Relations - Essay, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified Author - The Necessity for Non-White Models in the Development of the Major Revolutionary Artist - Essay (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified Author - Book of Illustrated Poetry - Poems (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified Author - Exorcism of the Straight/Man/Demon - Poem (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified Author - Unidentified Title - Story (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified Author - Adam Clayton Powell, Esther James - Chapters (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified Author - Ghetto Book - Typescript of Book, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified Authors, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Scripts
    - Baraka, Amiri - A Recent Killing - Script (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Bezaleel, Khalil, N.B. - The Black Disciple - Screenplay (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Fuller, Hoyt
      - The Candidate - Script, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - Garvey - Screenplay, 1973 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - In My Many Names and Days - Annotated, Script, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Goss, Clay - Ornette - Script, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Harrison, Paul Carter - Top-hat (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Himes, Terry - Baby Sister (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Howard, Terry - Nepal, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Hudson, Earnest L. - My Kingdom Come (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Hughes, Aisha - Voodoo America, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Jordan, Norman - When a Woman Gets Blue (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Kain, Gylan - Epitaph to the Coagulated Trinity, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - King, Jr., Woodie - Harlem Transfer - Screenplay Treatment (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Lovelace, Earl - The Schoolmaster - Screenplay (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Roemer, Michael and Young, Robert - Nothing But a Man - Screenplay, 1963 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Sackler, Howard - The Great White Hope - Screenplay - Revised First Draft, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Sloan, Anthony A Mystic Wind (no date/all time/this space): The Works of Henry Dumas Adapted to the Stage” (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Smyrl, David Langston - On the Lock-In, 1976-1977 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Vose, Kenneth and DuKore, Lawrence - Good Ol' Boy - Screenplay, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Ward, Douglas Turner - Happy Ending and Day of Absence, 1963 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Wexler, Norman - Mandingo - Second Revision - Screenplay, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified Author
    - Riot, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Untitled - Incomplete - Screenplay (Box 45, Folder 11)